{
    "id": "9663da5bd6df4ed1ab6928f93af9c7ea",
    "title": "Active And Passive Voice Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Rabid dogs ………………………… by forest rangers in Maine last year.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action. Something is done to it.",
            "answers": [
                "destroyed",
                "were destroying",
                "were destroyed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "257ef878e864469c92f1c9e6a3f62a77"
        },
        {
            "question": "His racy lifestyle ……………………….. many women.",
            "description": "We need an active verb here because the subject is the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "fascinated",
                "were fascinated",
                "had been fascinated"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4b230f6266f24597a3bd0c8f9e7cd424"
        },
        {
            "question": "The defeated candidate ………………………….. up and down in a rage.",
            "description": "We need an active verb here because the subject is the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "was stamped",
                "stamped",
                "has stamped"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ee5ac28c51694174bdb1d4251a003142"
        },
        {
            "question": "All those in favor should ………………………….. their hands.",
            "description": "To raise is to lift something.",
            "answers": [
                "raise",
                "rise",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7522044c373b4b079cd55d7ef2560865"
        },
        {
            "question": "We all ……………………….. when the judge entered the court.",
            "description": "To rise is to get up on one’s own accord.",
            "answers": [
                "rose",
                "raised",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4cf1abaaa7b04737a91038d4f660c36e"
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………………………. to stroll around the neighorhood on sunny afternoons.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about likes and preferences.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "likes",
                "were liked",
                "are liked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d78c9a0cfea141f3baf0a39226d08161"
        },
        {
            "question": "The company ……………………….. a large range of products.",
            "description": "Since there is no reference to past time, we use the simple present tense here. ",
            "answers": [
                "produce",
                "produces",
                "produced"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "feba2afe30de454fa871a1995b9af9d0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Buying a boat ……………………….. low on my list of priorities.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the –ing form buying. When a gerund is the subject, the verb is usually singular.",
            "answers": [
                "rank",
                "ranks",
                "have ranked"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "35169338e1af4c7685a306ee0cba5537"
        },
        {
            "question": "His rapacious ways ………………………… him wealthy but friendless.",
            "description": "We use the simple past tense to simply state that something happened.",
            "answers": [
                "made",
                "was made",
                "has been made"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fcc1691893a8461691dacbe833696489"
        },
        {
            "question": "He rarely …………………………, yet he passed every exam.",
            "description": "When one verb is in the past tense, the other verb will most probably also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "study",
                "studied",
                "was studied"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9372869d409149668ad24a6a4d1f7805"
        },
        {
            "question": "I rate that performance one of the best I ……………………………",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is more common with indefinite time expressions like ever and never.",
            "answers": [
                "ever saw",
                "have ever seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a8e5cf42beba43d0a139994dfcb520c7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each flood victim ………………………….. with a daily ration.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "provided",
                "was provided",
                "has provided"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1b598b3c341d43eeb4598e26ad8ee7cd"
        }
    ]
}